1983-0723 找到你的位置 下, Lodge山 交流会
Bhaiyakayataya prabhu zachare
Sarva bhi saraghi prabhu mayexari
Purna jaya ji vachari
Bhaiyakayataya prabhu zachare
Jagat vichere upakara sauv
Parina jaju jag kachari
Bhaiyakayataya prabhu zachare
lthi nirdhana paratra jacha
Sarva dhanacha sachari
Bhaiyakayataya prabhu zachare
Adhi vyadhi varana varati
Paya asha purusha chari
Bhaiyakayataya prabhu zachare
非常感谢
谁帮我翻译…
这首歌是我们家一个亲戚写的
他皈依基督教 是自觉的灵
他没法适应皈依体制
还有印度教徒对待彼此的方式
种姓制度 所有这一切
他非常会写
写了很多赞美诗
这是其中一首
这首歌
我在小时候经常唱
歌词大意是这样的
那些得到神的人
那些拥有神的人
他们为什么要恐惧
那些
走来走去的
我不知道英文怎么说
云游人
那些到处旅行的人
为了神和为别人做好事
但他不属于这个世界
这样的人没有恐惧
他站在上面
语言 马拉地语
是非常浓烈的语言 它遍及很多角落
当你说马拉地语 像这样
"Adhi Vyadhi Varana Varati Payi Asha Purusha Chari."
意思是一个这样有能力的人站在上面
他的脚超越疾病
心理问题
和死亡本身
但当你如此说
这种人的脚在它之上
也意味着 他的脚能有效力
克服这些问题
它是一种双关语
像这样的人 他的脚在这三样东西上面
疾病 心理问题 死亡
脚在这些之上
这说明 这样的人是高于这些问题的
因此 如果有这样水准的人
他的脚接触病人
或精神不正常的人
或死人
这样的人会提升他们
可以带他们出来
它具有双重意义
所以整首歌都是这样
那些属于神的
那些拥有神的
不应该有恐惧
不应该感到沮丧
今天我非常需要它
因为一方面
我很高兴看到这么多霎哈嘉瑜伽士 真正的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
不是假装的弟子或者演员
而是真正的 高水准的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
还有一些人站在外围
这么长时间一直在外围
有些时候 我看到十分危险
他们会被毁灭
这时 你需要这样的一首歌
在童年时 我感到绝望的时候
我会唱这首歌
这是一首非常感人的歌
好吧
但我不能一字一句的说
我现在不想这样
这首歌令我非常感动
这就是 Rutambhara  Pragnya.
今天我非常想听这首歌
所以今天早上我告诉你们这一点新的认识
Pragnya. 'Gnya' 是知识的意思
'Pra' 意思是觉醒的知识
来自于冥想的知识
冥想的寄托
三昧是其效果
就像果实成熟
当果实成熟 你尝到味道
甘甜的果实
然后你开始看到周围
自然 神
如何甜蜜地和你玩耍
必须达到这种状态
对于每一个哈嘉瑜珈 重要的是
他们必须达到这一境界
因为 除非你已经达到这个最低标准
你们会仍然处于危险地带
这一点让我很不安
所以每个人都必须达到这个状态
你们每天都要看到神的祝福的体现
这意味着你们进入神的国
这是神的国
在这里你们被照料 保护 引导
被带到上天的极乐处
通过物质表现形式
通过精神的体现
通过钱财体现
通过关系体现
通过那么多事情体现
也通过自然体现
你看到太阳 月亮 星星 天堂
所有五大元素都帮助你们
这种状态 大家都要实现
所有人 所有人都应该达到
然后才能开始更高的升进
那么如何达到这个境界 这是个常见的问题
我今天告诉你们 第一件事
你们是非常幸运的人
相对于其他的求道者
那些过去的 将来的 现在的求道者
因为许多事情都是
用来让求道者克服的
你们不用克服
比如他们冥想
用一些神的名号
注意力会不断地重复名号
祈求神
或者思考神和那些
但整个事情是机械的
他们总会跳到某种
低级的所谓的神力 意味着他们被附身
那些人开始用名号 比如罗摩
你们看到过很多那样的人
他们开始跳
他们的行为变得可笑
因此 注意力不但没有集中
反而非常的不安
变成可笑的注意力 不稳定
当注意力变得不稳定
一种左脉的东西进入他们
他们会很享受
就像一个醉汉很享受
然后这些人会哭泣
享受他们的哭泣 麻烦别人
他们没有力量去克服
他们会被附身
另一种是 有抱负的人
比如我们有很多科学家 这样的人
有抱负的人 他们会自我催眠
认为自己很了不起
表现地很愚蠢
他们也会被附体
你们可以看到 希特勒 诸如此类的人
今天有很多这样的人
他们统治世界
在民主国家和共产国家都有
他们大多数其实都是豪强
这就是为什么今天有那么混乱
像什么民族主义
或类似的东西 他们会发展
尝试利用这些
右脉的人 让他们参与战争
和各种破坏性的事情
这种注意力
属于自以为是的人
比如 印度教 基督教 大部分都是好战分子
穆斯林 今天的穆斯林都好战
而且内部争斗不休 这就是最讽刺的地方
基督教也是 内部战争不断
印度教也是内部争斗
比如只有两个国家
印度教占大多数 所谓的
一个是尼泊尔 一个是印度
这两个国家整天吵架
没有一天消停
没有听到关于他们吵架的消息
因为印度教徒不用剑
但整天处于非常冷血的争吵
就是这种情况
以神的名义 我再次说
因为他们在一个非常不同的水平开始
他们的注意力去了左边或右边
他们发展这些神通
所以我们还能怎么办
首先 因为神的恩典 我告诉你们
你们都是自觉的人
你们的升进是在中间
这是非常非常困难的
绝对困难的 毫无疑问
但是你们应该学会保持在中间
但是 如何保持注意力在中间
是许多人的问题
他们仍然没有高于自己
当你们冥想
尝试持续的冥想 首先保持住
然后 你发现
你正渐入三昧
也就是一种状态
你开始感到喜悦
和神祝福的幸福
然后开始说 神啊 多好的祝福
多好的祝福 多好的祝福
当你达到那个状态
你必须明白自己是谁
你是谁
你是什么
你是灵
在你建立对灵的持续注意力之后
你会发展出一种状态
在喜悦中的静观状态
在座各位
可以用这种方式简单自测
如果想要最好的房间
需要提前十天预订
他们必须如此才能得到好房间
如果想要最好的食物
或者最好的时间 尝试在头脑中有个位置
诚实面对自己
霎哈嘉瑜伽是个诚实的努力
为自己最好的隐私
你们都应该面对自己
夫妻要有自己的隐私
这个交流会不是夫妇们的聚会
或者让你们大声说话 走动 找乐子
不 你们来这里是为了冥想
对我来说时间很短
因为人们花了几千天
建立冥想的状态
但在这种快速的生活
你们必须建立强度
所以进入冥想状态 有些人觉得
他们是来度假的
但这里没有大海
那么怎么游泳呢 这样的心情
还有一些人不这么想
但也要求更多的舒适
我吃不上饭 我应该有这个
最好的给我孩子
或者给我丈夫或妻子 我的
没关系 你们只是住一晚上
男士住在一起 女士住在一起
如果有孩子 没关系
但没有必要夫妻睡在一起
这种时候 你们都在一个房间冥想
你们是为了一个非常特殊的目标来到这里
你们为它付了钱
所以要冥想
我发现 每个人都大声说话
我觉得他们没有在冥想状态
每个人都认为很享受这里
很不错 很好
所有这些想法都是旧观念
静默必须在内在和外在建立
我必须说 对于这一点 当然印度人
他们知道这些 所以我不会称为印度素质
但澳大利亚
澳大利亚 我在那些灵舍都住过
在悉尼我们有50到60人住在那里
每天我从来没听到过声音
甚至没听到过脚步 直到我在那里
当我在那里 我不是在那里住一天
我在那里住10天 15天
甚至没有来回走动和孩子哭闹的声音 什么声音都没有
我从来听不到声音
这是可以控制注意力的方法之一
在我面前 你说什么
你说什么
你必须知道这是礼仪的一部分
你在跟谁说话
你们不要开玩笑 不能开玩笑
我可以讲笑话
有时你们可以笑 没关系 或者有时可以大笑
但这些都要有分量
你们跟谁说话 原因是
我告诉你们这些
因为这些关系
这些行为都会帮助你们
对我没有帮助
也不会拯救我
我不会得到我的自觉
而是你们要从我这里获得好处
因此要稳固你们的注意力
我见到那些跟我一起住的人
有时我故意叫他们来 看看有什么问题
那些跟我住的人 我发现
变得更加精微和深入
有些人开始利用
自由散漫 过着一种生活
平凡又愚蠢
我无法理解
因此这种意识应该在你们的心里
时间是非常重要的
你们来这里 是非常非常重要的时间
而且 当你们和我在一起
是重要的时间里最重要的时间
从历史上看 这是最重要的时刻
应该充分利用
有些人认为 如果他们可以从我这里获得一些钱
那才叫做利用 好吧 你们可以利用
有些人认为如果他们可以用一些我的时间
那样才叫利用 好吧 你们可以拿去
或者有些人认为他们可以利用我
是那种自我纵容或什么
我是个大老爷之类的想法
好吧
但是 明智的人最会利用
他们利用这个机会在内在生长
所以第一意识必须是
你们是这样幸运的人
在你们面前站着的人
她可以控制所有的轮穴
控制所有的力量 或者说是全能的
你们如何利用这种优势
是非常重要的
我现在住在两个地方 可以这样说
主要是英国和印度
我觉得英国和印度有很多差别
在印度 我越住越觉得他们变得很强调礼仪
因为他们有悠久的传统训练
但是在英国我发现 人们开始利用他们的优势
开玩笑 讲笑话
你们不能
这不同于取悦
但这属于轻浮
跟深入的人浅薄地打交道
例如如果有一块锡板
你把它拿到尼亚加拉大瀑布下面
锡板会怎样
它是完全无法承受的
所以尽管Rutambhara Pragnya 就像今天的太阳
昨天你们一定很不舒服 心想
我们来到这里 还要住帐篷
而且还在下雨
我知道你们许多人一定这么想
但达到那种状态的人会想
这有什么 如果我住在这里也没关系
我来这里是为了一个特殊的目的
只要我达到这个目的 其他我都不在乎
什么不舒适 所有这些事情
我要达到那个目的
你们有些人不能近距离地看到我
有些人还不能 没关系
最重要的是
我要达到那种状态 这是我来这里的目的
不是为了好玩 不是为了食物 也不是寻求舒适
不为任何东西 只是为了达到特殊的状态
这里我成为导师
我应该做哪些准备
我们必须非常小心
因为神的注意力
不是直接提升你们
它是一个平衡
你们始终在一个平衡 记住这个
你们必须非常小心
你们是否平衡
你们如何进步
没关心 不用担心 关于太阳
我喜欢它
我今天早上叫他来
那么 你们如何管理这注意力
让我们来看看注意力有几种状态
你的注意力会成为狡猾的注意力
你看任何事 都从狡猾的角度去看
在自我型社会 很多人都发展出这种注意力
而且 如果你被狡猾的邪灵附体
那么只有神能救你和其他人了
狡猾的注意力会是
你看到任何事 你开始思考
这对我有什么便宜可占
我可以省多少钱 你们看
它非常非常快
这样做会更便宜
如果我走这条路会省不少时间
你们看 省英镑 省时间
省所有东西 把自己都省了
所以你就一直这样省
如果你尝试省钱 注意力会变得狡猾
这里省 那里省
自己不断计算
但如果你们尝试自然而然地省钱
事实上没什么可试的
只是那么发生 你就能节省
但狡猾的注意力不断地尝试
在事情上耍小聪明
它论证 它解释
这样会更好… 这些天
有这个便宜便宜便宜的东西
这样你会真的发疯
就像有一次我去美国买机票
我说 不要给我昂贵的机票 头等舱没有
我可以坐经济舱
所以他们给了我一张票
用这张票 我怎么也回不到伦敦
至少一年都没回来
我将在美国英语里迷路
在某处
他们想出那么多办法
这班倒那班 再倒那班
那种恐怖的注意力毫无用处
丢掉它 忘掉它
如此省钱 我从没看到有人靠省钱变有钱
比如我想要去买一些涂料
我们买一些涂料
然后他们想 好吧 如果你带它回来
我们如何退货
我们应该这样那样 废话
头脑一直在那个层次
我再给你们一个例子 有一天
我们买涂料刷玻璃
看那精微的部分
你看 再粗糙层面总有精微的迹象
涂料被拿来
好像价值8分钱 很便宜
好吧 我能付得起
所以我买了
如果你付不起就不要买
他们说 现在我们应该退掉没用完的
我说 为什么 你们去退吧
你们花了那么多汽油去那里
如果你要计算 那也是愚蠢的
还有你们浪费的时间
但是母亲 你看 我们最终可以省两分钱
我说好吧
我会省很多钱 让我告诉你们怎么做
我取了那些涂料 涂了很多东西
有些像玻璃 有些像石头
所有东西看起来很漂亮
所以毁灭性的头脑只是计算
如果你们有这样的头脑
有自知之明 你们必须摆脱
那种计算
便宜便宜便宜便宜便宜
你们应该放弃 保持在中脉
当然 你们不应该过分放纵
但是你们也不应该总是
沉溺于这种计算
因为你们在浪费你们重要的觉醒的注意力
在这个世界很少有人有觉醒的注意力
必须知道你们是自觉的灵
你们不是普通 世俗的人
你们是特殊的人 你们不要浪费
你们的注意力在无用的金钱的计算上
一分钱这个那个
让我们继续前进 看看会发生什么
我从不计算 你们知道 但我生活地很节俭
你们也可以做到
这种注意力 狡猾的注意力
也是非常挑剔的注意力
它开始是省钱
然后 在晚上一定要喝酒
所以生下来的那些分分钱 都跑到
酒的排水沟里去了
都是罪 这种人的总和是多少
所以 这种心态必须被控制
特别是自我的人都特别爱计算
最令人惊讶
但印度人不爱算计
也不富有
他们很慷慨 他们总是有钱给霎哈嘉瑜伽
我跟他们从来都没有钱的问题 从来没有
因为他们不是如此计算
第他们来说 他们为他人 不是为自己 而是为他人
为别人花钱
如果他们来你家
好了 打开你的心 是花钱的时候了
而不是用来买酒 自我放纵
而是尽情地为别人做事
那是他们的实践和传统
所以在这方面 你们必须采取这个传统
哦 他们来了 现在让我们花钱吧
我们能做什么
这是你们需要明白的
那些非常自我放纵的人
are extremely miserly people.
是极度吝啬的人
So the attention which is cunning,
因此这注意力是狡猾的
is the worse attention, because you see,
是更差劲的注意力 因为你看
cunningness also cheats yourself. It is cunning with you,
这狡猾同样也欺骗你自己 是在对你狡猾
and you think, "Oh I've been smart enough, you see,
而你却认为 噢 我已经很聪明了 你看
I've saved two p".
我已经节约了两分钱
But you have lost your soul.
但是你已经失去你的灵魂了
You are no more a Sahaja Yogi.
你已经不是霎哈嘉瑜伽仕了
I'll give you an example.
我要给你一个例子
I told somebody that,
我告诉过一些人
"Keep the van down there, go by train,
不要坐货车 坐火车去
this van seems to be a horrible van."
这个货车看起来是一个非常可怕的货车
And there was a lot of a, you see, explanation,
而且那有很多 你看 解释
with both the fingers going on like this to Me, you see,
两个手指都像这样 你看
and I got so fed up with the bomb shells coming on Me
我对这种炮弹忍无可忍
that I said, to go ahead.
就是我说的  还是去做了
And the thing fell,
然后这个事情变糟
and the thing got spoilt or whatever it is,
然后这个事情变坏或者不管怎样
is out of order now.
现在完全混乱了
So they had to do what I was telling them.
所以 他们必须去做那些我告诉他们的事情
Without the bomb shell, if they had listened to Me
再也没有炮弹 如果他们听我的
it would have been all right.
就没有问题
So your attention should not be on saving material things
因此 你们的注意力不应该放在节省物质的东西
and worldly things and all that,
和所有那些世俗的东西
but attention itself must be saved.
但是注意力自己必须要被节省
Ask a question, "Where is my attention?".
问一个问题 我的注意力在哪里
I've seen in the programs
我就看见在活动中
some people are concentratedly listening to me,
一些人非常专注地听我讲话
but some people cannot.
但有些人就不是
Some are concentrated for a short while,
一些人只能专注一小会儿
and some get disinterested after some time.
而有些听一会儿后就不感兴趣了
Some are looking here. Some are looking there.
一些看这儿 一些看那儿
So how much attention you have saved is the only concern
那么到底你节省了多少注意力是仅仅关注
of a Sahaja Yogi. Forget about others,
一个霎哈嘉瑜伽仕 忘记其他人
they are all garbage cleaners, you see.
他们都是垃圾清洁工 你看
Forget about others who are not seeking,
忘记那些没有求道的人
who are not of your quality, but you are a quality.
那些不具备你的品质的人 但是你是一个精品
Now what do you have to save?
现在你应该节省什么
For example somebody is a king.
例如 有个人是一个国王
He doesn't bother of two p being saved.
他没有因为节省了两分钱而被烦扰
I don't know baba, these days, I can't say definitely!
我不知道 现在的社会 我不敢肯定
They must be also doing that kind of a thing, you know, but
他们一定也做着这种类型的事情 你知道 但是
what is he bothered to save his grace, to dignity.
而使他烦恼的是节省他的仁慈 他的尊贵
But for a Sahaja Yogi the most important thing is,
但是对于一个霎哈嘉瑜伽仕来说 最重要的事情是
you must save your attention.
你必须节省你的注意力
It's called as Chitta Nirodha.
它被称作 Chitta Nirodha
Nirodh -- is saving of your attention.
Nirodh是节省 你的注意力
"Where is it going, It's such a precious thing for me.
它到哪里去了 对我来说它是多么珍贵的东西
Where is it running?"
它跑哪里去了
Then how do you save your attention?
然后怎样才能节约你的注意力
Is through concentration.
就是通过专注
Concentrate. Try to concentrate.
全神贯注 尝试着全神贯注
Don't allow your attention to wobble.
不要让你的注意力游移不定
Gradually you will develop concentration.
慢慢地你要发展专注力
You can watch My photograph, it's the best.
你可以注视我的照片 这是最好的
Concentrate, bring it in your heart,
全神贯注 把它带到你的心中
let it be integrated in your heart.
让它与你的心合一
You are lucky people,
你们是幸运的人
you don't have to build up a photograph,
你们不用去树立一个照片
and then give it up because it is just a Avalambana,
然后放弃它 因为它只是一个Avalambana
means it's just a dependence,
意思是它只是一个依赖
and then you remove it.
然后你移走它
It's a complete dependence for you
对你来说它就是完全的依靠
and a load for Me -- of complete joy.
对我来说就是负载 完全的喜乐
So when you are concentrating in Sahaja Yoga,
因此当你全神贯注于霎哈嘉瑜伽
absolutely fully in Sahaja Yoga,
完全倾注在霎哈嘉瑜伽
then you are controlling, saving, your attention.
然后你就会控制 节省你的注意力
This is one type of people.
这是一种类型的人
Then the another type of an attention, what we call,
然后 另一种类型的注意力 我们称它什么
are the people who are sort of take a very negative attitude.
是那些持有非常负面态度的一类人
The first are the positive, so called,
这第一种是正面的 所谓的
so called positive,
所谓的积极
who are saving money, saving everything that is useless.
那些节约钱 节约一切的人 节省那没用的
Now the second type are the archbishops of all that is disaster,
那这第二种是所有灾难的大主教
misery, mishaps
悲惨 灾祸
This type of an attention.
这种类型的注意力
If you read newspaper every morning
如果你每天早上看一下报纸
you will have an attention like that.
你就会有那种类型的注意力
All the newspaper people have that kind of an attention,
所有看报纸的人们就有那种类型的注意力
to find where is the disaster.
去看看哪里有灾难
I mean, in a sinister way,
我的意思是 用一种灾难性的方式
they feel happy there's a disaster.
有灾难的话他们就会感到开心
I've seen people, "Oh Mother, I came to the seminar
我见过一些人 噢 母亲 我来参加交流会
but the problem is, you see, there was no water."
但是问题是 你看 没有水
The attention is in finding disasters
这个注意力在寻找灾难上
within and without.
从内到外
"What happened?", "There's a disaster",
发生了什么   好不幸啊
"What happened?" "I lost the pin".
怎么回事  我丢了一个别针
Absurd, to have such stupid ideas.
太荒谬 有这样愚蠢的想法
They will cry and weep and make everyone miserable,
他们要哭喊 让每个人都感觉悲惨
"Oooh, I'm so miserable."
噢 我好悲惨
"What?", "My husband doesn't talk to me",
怎么了 我的丈夫不跟我说话
or "My child is not with me."
或者 我的孩子不跟我
Such people are extremely self-indulgent
这样的人是极度任性的
as far as their relationships are concerned.
直至涉及他们的人际关系
They make everyone like that,
他们让每个人都像那样
"Oh, the person didn't talk to me nicely
噢 那个人和我说话不和善
and he was this way and that way."
他这样 那样
They feel hurt at the slightest touch
轻轻碰一下 他们都感觉受伤害
and by that they think they are saving their emotions
通过那样 他们认为他们在节省自己的情感
if not the material things.
如果那不是物质的东西
Such people are very frightened people to talk to anyone,
这样的人跟任何人说话都担惊受怕的
and anybody says nice things also, they get a fright,
任何人说一些美好的事情 他们都受惊吓
like this, they'll frown.
就像这样 他们就会皱眉
The reason is they do not know what they have to save,
这个原因就是他们不知道什么才是他们应该节省的东西
is not their emotions at all.
根本不是他们的情感
There's no need to save your emotions, you are protected.
根本没有必要节省你们的情感 你们是被保护的
What does it matter if somebody says anything to you,
如果别人跟你们说任何事又怎么样呢
you are above there, nobody can touch you!
你是超越那些的 没有人可以触碰你
You are wasting your attention all the time
你一直浪费你的注意力
by trying to save your emotions.
来尝试节省你的情感
There's nothing to be frightened of anyone,
对任何人都没有什么好怕的
because somebody is going to say something, harsh word,
因为一些人要说一些话 刺耳的话
that's why you don't want to do something.
这就是你不想做一些事情的原因
Such compromising people, so called,
这样妥协的人 因此就叫做
have not understood Sahaja Yoga.
对霎哈嘉瑜伽没有理解的人
There is no compromise in Sahaja Yoga at all.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽里是没有任何妥协的
It is just like a diamond.
霎哈嘉瑜伽就像一颗钻石
Diamond will remain a diamond whatever you do,
钻石将一直是钻石 不管你做什么
it's for ever and ever,
它就永远
it's like that.
它就像那样
So one has to understand that the attention should not be allowed
因此你要明白 这样的注意力是不应该被允许的
to drift into this kind of an indulgence
偏离到一种放纵的
which is of a drunkard,
那种具有酒鬼性质的
that, they are the most miserable people, the drunkards are
那样 他们就是最悲惨的人 那些酒鬼们
Just imagine. They'll be always crying, weeping,
就想象一下 他们将经常哭喊 哭泣
and people would think they are very miserable.
人们会认为他们是非常悲惨的
So what you have to save at that time is your attention
因此在那种时候 你必须要节省的就是你的注意力
from such indulgences
从那样的放纵中
into useless expression of your fear
到对你恐惧的无用的表达
about your emotions.
关于你情感的
See now, today they sang the song.
你看现在 今天他们唱这首歌
The song did fill Me.
这首歌确实让我满足
Completely brought out some of the expressions
完全把一些表达带出来了
which would not spontaneously come out at this time.
那些在这个时间本来没法自动流露出来的感情
But the greatest thing it has done is to remind Me
但是这些最伟大的事情已经完成 就是来提醒我
that, "You are God. You are not to get frustrated,
你是上帝 你不能变得沮丧
You have to look after all of them,
你要照顾所有人
and You are powerful.
而且你是充满力量的
How dare to suspect yourself or feel frustrated.
怎敢怀疑你自己 或者感到受挫呢
That thing which is so much reflecting,
那是一个非常有反映的事
like a mirror, I see My mirror
就像一面镜子 我看见我在镜子里
In the same way you should also
同样的方式 你也应该
have your emotional understanding
有对你的情感的理解
and the emotion should be a mirror,
而这情感应该是一面镜子
you should see yourself in your emotions,
你应该在你的情感里看到你自己
how you behave, how you treat, how you talk
你的行为怎样 你怎样处事 你怎样言谈
So such people should always keep a mirror
因此这样的人应该总是有一面镜子
and feel elevated.
然后感觉被提升了
You are a Sahaja Yogi
你就是一名霎哈嘉瑜伽仕
and the mirror, in the reflection, you should see Me and not yourself.
而那镜子 在那反映中 你应该看见我而不是你自己
Sometimes I've an eye that really frustrated with Sahaja Yogis,
有时候 我发现 真的对一些练习者很泄气
very much. Then I just stand before the mirror
非常 然后我就只是站在镜子面前
and I say, "Now, come along.
然后我说 现在 打起精神来
You are the one who has all the powers,
你是拥有一切力量的人
who has all the chakras awakened.
是所有的轮穴都被唤醒的人
None of the Advents had this.
没有一个降世神祇是这样的
You are the one who has created this world
你是那创造世界的人
and You are the one who has to save it. So now, get up."
而你也是那拯救它的人 所以现在 打起精神来
Not to lose courage,
不要失去勇气
not to worry.
不要去担忧
Only in the emotional things I sometimes
只有在情感方面的一些事我有的时候
feel that now I'll have to give up some of them, completely.
感觉现在我要放弃他们中的一些 完全地
They are My children, as a Mother, not as a Guru.
他们是我的孩子 作为一个母亲 不是作为一个导师
For a Guru they don't have problem.
作为一个导师 他们没有问题
And then the stirring up comes in, within Myself that,
然后  热情又被激起  在我内在
"No, even if I have to give up, doesn't matter, I have to raise,
不 尽管我要放弃 没关系 我要再唤起
absolutely", and with that power it works.
完全地 那力量自己运作
So the reflection should be of Me,
因此这反映应该是具有我的性质
of something that is ideal before you,
有一些是在你之前想象的
the one that gives you energy, like this song
是那给予你能量的 就像这首歌
and not the reflection of a miserable person.
而不是那些可悲的人的反映
Christ who's standing before you
耶稣 他就站在你的面前
as in the Sistine Chapel and not some miserable skeleton
就像在（罗马梵蒂冈的）西斯廷教堂 而不是那些可悲的干枯的人
which is even worse than you.
那些比你们还要差劲的人
So create those images of your Mother
因此 创造那些有关你们的母亲的想象
which you should see in your emotions and rise.
那些你应该在你的情感中看见而提升的
This is the second type of attention you have to control.
这就是第二种你需要控制的注意力
The third one is a very horrid idiotic one.
这第三种是一种非常可怕的白痴的一种
The idiotic one comes from the second type,
这种白痴的 从第二种而来
where the person is emotionally indulgent.
来自于那种情感上放纵型的
That is the "A" of the third.
那是第三种的A型
And the "B" of the third comes from the first type,
而这第三种的B型来自于第一种
which is stupid. So we have two types of people,
是那种愚蠢的 因此我们有两种人
one idiotic and another are stupid.
一种白痴而另一种是愚蠢
But in Indian language there's only one word,
但是在印度语里只有一个单词
specially in Marathi -- is murkha.
尤其是在马拉地语里---是murkha
For them both categories are the same,
对他们来说两种类型都是一样的
as if the circle meets at the same point.
就像是画圈最后又在同一点相遇
I mean English language in some ways is good
我的意思是英语在某些地方是很好的
at least it differentiates between the murkhas,
至少对不同类型的愚蠢有区分
like they can be stupid or they can be idiotic, you see.
就像他们可以是蠢货或者他们可以是白痴 你看
Because of psyche being so confused here,
因为灵魂在这里非常困惑
that psychologists have brought out. Some are schizophrenic,
心理学家已经说出 一些是精神分裂者
some are idiots, some are stupid, some are donkeys.
一些是白痴 一些是蠢货 一些是傻瓜
So this, the third type is the worst, is most frustrating for Me.
因此这样 这第三种是最差劲的 对我来说是最让我沮丧的
They'll stick onto Me like leeches,
他们吸附着我 就像水蛭
they'll be saying stupid things all the time.
他们总是会说一些愚蠢的事情
Just can't bear an idiot, isn't it?
实在是不能忍受一个白痴 难道不是吗
They can bore a person. I mean all sorts of this put together
他们令人厌恶 我的意思是各种各样的在一起
is called as murkha.
就叫做 murkha
So I don't want to analyze it, it's a bit too much.
所以我不想分析它 有点儿太多了
So that kind of an attention you have, then you better keep quiet.
因此你要有那种注意力  然后你最好保持沉默
Don't talk. Just listen to others what they talk, what they say.
不要说话 只是听其他人怎么说 他们说什么
There are some people who will just go on talking, talking, talking,
有一些人他们就只会滔滔不绝 一直说 说  说
irrelevantly, uselessly, wasting their energy,
不切题地 没用地 浪费他们的能量
and such people are always friends of the cunning.
而这样的人他们经常和狡猾的人是朋友
The cunning and such people go hand in hand,
狡猾的人和这样的人一起手拉手
because the cunning wants to befool someone,
因为狡猾的人想愚弄一些人
and the fool wants to be befooled.
而那些傻瓜也想被愚弄
Like a king will have a jester,
就像 有一个国王就会有一个小丑
it's like that you see, these combinations work out.
就像那样 你看 这样的组合能够成
So for such people the best thing is to keep quiet.
因此对这样的人来说 最好保持沉默
Preserve all their attention,
保护他们所有的注意力
all their energies just for cleansing.
他们所有的能量只为清理
All this idiocity will pass away very soon
所有的这些白痴将很快消失
if you try to preserve yourself. Don't talk,
如果你要保护你自己 就不要说话
don't say things which are stupid,
不要说一些愚蠢的话
which are idiotic, just keep quiet, and watch others.
那些白痴的话 只是保持静默 然后静观他人
Sometimes such people can become very great vehicle
有时 这样的人可以变成非常好的工具
of God's power,
上帝的力量
but if they do not take to stupidity and idiocy.
但是 如果他们不要变成蠢货和白痴
This is the type of people, three types I would say,
这就是这种类型的人 我要说的三种类型
but the fourth type are the people who lead a life of concentration.
但是这第四种类型的是那些过着非常专注生活的人
I mean a person who is working very hard,
我的意思是这种人工作非常刻苦
say, in the office, is a very remarkably successful person,
也就是说 在办公室 是非常卓有成效的人
and this and that, and that, and that, and that,
就是这样 那样 这样 那样
is also very concentrated.
非常地全神贯注
Somebody who works very well, anywhere,
那些工作非常好的大人物 任何一个地方
with a concentrated mind, is concentrated.
都有一个专注的思想 非常地专注
A housewife who looks after her husband and children is very concentrated,
一个家庭主妇 照顾她的丈夫和孩子是非常专注的
and a husband who looks after his family
而一个丈夫他照顾他的家庭
and his things in a very concentrated way.
和他的事情也是一种非常专注的方式
They know how to paint（plan？） well, they know how to do things,
他们知道怎样画好画（计划） 他们知道怎么把事情做好
and their hands are deft, and they know everything.
他们的双手非常灵巧 他们知道所有的一切
But such people can have a very immobile attention,
但是这样的人 他们会有一种非常固化的注意力
very immobile, like plastic,
非常固化的 就像塑料
or you can call it, like rubber.
或者你可以称它 就像橡胶
At the most, to improve on it, we can say,
至多 要改进它 我们可以说
like some of the things I have seen which you use
就像一些东西我看到过你们用来
for damp-proofing, you see,
防潮的 你看
you just apply it, after some time it's just parched, into it.
你们只是运用它  过一段时间后 它就干透了 陷进去
They just can't get out of it.
他们就没法把它去掉了
They just can't. They can't enjoy anything.
他们不能 他们不能享受任何东西
Unless and until you show them a file you can't talk to them.
除非或者知道你给他们拿出一个文件 不然你没法和他们谈话
You see, if you have to talk to such a person,
你看 如果你要和这样的人说话
better take a file before you,
最好准备一个文件
and before starting you put the file before you.
而且在开始之前 你要在你面前放上一个文件
If it is on the file only, they will see,
如果在文件上 他们才会看
but if you talk, they say, "Make a file."
但是如果你说话 他们会说 做一个文件
Very parched, and they cannot enjoy life.
非常地干焦 而他们是不能享受生命的
There's no mobility, they cannot be creative.
没有灵活性可言 他们没有创造性
They can be creative only as far as their style is concerned,
他们可以有创造性 只有和他们的风格是相关的
but not the creative of the joy.
但是 不是创造性的喜乐
So that kind of concentration is there,
因此哪种类型的专注就是那样
concentrated effort people put in.
高度集中注意力的人
Like there are people who are fanatics.
就像那些狂热的人
They are very concentrated in their effort, extremely.
他们对他们的成果非常地专注 极度地
That's how all these religions have spread, like Christianity,
这就是所有这些宗教如何得以传播 就像基督教
Islam, Hinduism and all that,
伊斯兰教 印度教 和所有那些
because they had a concentrated effort of fanaticism
因为他们有一种专心致志努力的狂热
concentrated effort.
专心致志的努力
If you read the letters of Paul in the Bible,
如果你读了这些在圣经中保罗的信
you will see the concentration of it:
你就会看到这种专注
"You go there and you go there and establish a church and do this"
你去那里 你去那里 然后建一个教堂 然后做这些
and "What you have done?". Very organized, very systematic,
你都完成了什么 非常有组织 非常系统化
absolutely moving like a belt on a machine.
完全就像在一个机器上运行的流水线
And they all the time have that after effects of that movement.
而且他们总会有那样的后遗症
Charlie Chaplin has shown in his picture "Modern Times".
查理·卓别林 已经在他的摩登时代影片中展现
I used to enjoy that very much,
我以前非常喜欢看那个影片
that he used to tie up a belt, you see, standing
他常常拧螺丝 你看 站着
for about an hour, and then
站大约一个小时 然后
after some time when he was released of the job,
一段时间后当他已经从这个事中解脱
he used to go on like that.
他还是习惯继续像那样
That kind of an attention,
那种类型的注意力
that is concentrated, means stuck onto something.
那就是集中的 意思是执着于一些事
It's not that, it's not penetrating.
它不是那样的 它不是渗透的
Because if your attention doesn't become, by concentration,
因为如果你的注意力没有变成  仅靠专注
subtler and subtler, then it is not that
越来越精微的 然后 它就不是那么回事了
but it is getting stuck, and the stuck attention
它变得卡住了 那个卡住的注意力
is of no use for Sahaja Yoga.
对霎哈嘉来说是没什么用的
Such people, I do not know, will never be saved perhaps.
这样的人 我不知道 可能永远也不会被拯救
So called successful.
所谓的成功
They'll go with all their badges, everything,
他们会走到哪里都带着他们的勋章 所有的东西
and God will say, "Go back gentlemen,
然后上帝会说 回去吧 绅士们
you are not yet been passed through the customs."
你们还没过海关
There is another organization,
这是另一种组织
which works much faster, much smarter way,
他运作得更快 用更聪明的方式
and a very specially efficient thing.
而且特别得有效率
So these people will be just 'stuck' people.
因此这样的人将只会成为 执著的人
Now there are fourth type of people which are concentrated.
现在有四种专注型的人
They are intense, deep.
他们结实 很深
They penetrate
他们渗透
because they are living minds.
因为他们有活跃的思想
Theirs are not dead, parched minds, they have living mind,
它们没有死 干焦的思想 他们有活着的头脑
they penetrate.
他们渗透
I watch sometimes, I ask some people
有时候我观察 我问一些人
what do you think of a particular person?
你会认为某个特定的人怎么样
Immediately I know, what they talk.
马上我就知道 他们要说什么
If they just talk in a mundane way,
如果他们只是以世俗的方式说
"He is a fine person, he is a bad person, this thing, that thing",
他是一个好人 他是一个坏人 这些 那些的
then I know what it is. Very superficial, shallow.
然后我就知道是怎么回事了 非常表面 肤浅
But a person who sees the possibilities and the potentialities of
但是看到发展可能和潜能
it's awakening, and the problems a person is facing,
正在被唤醒的人 以及那个人正在面临的问题
then I know that he is the one who has that concentration
然后我就知道他就是那个有专注力
into the subject.
在那个课题上的人
And the subject of Sahaja Yoga requires the maximum,
而霎哈嘉瑜伽的课题需要最大的限度
maximum, penetration, because Sahaja Yoga,
最大的限度 渗透 因为霎哈嘉瑜伽
if you have understood, I don't know if you have understood
如果你已经理解 我不知道你是否已经理解
or you are aware of it or not,
或者你是否意识到
but is learned through experience and through nothing else.
但是是通过经历来学习的 不是其他任何东西
You have to experience and then believe into it.
你必须去经验 然后相信它
It is not that what I told you is a conditioning on your mind,
它不是我告诉你的东西在你脑海中形成制约
nothing, you experience it yourself and learn.
什么都不是 是你自己经验它然后学习
But those who have that penetrating intelligence,
但是那些有渗透性理解力的人
who have that penetrating love, emotions
他们有那种渗透性的爱 情感
and those [who] have that penetrating movement
而那些有那种渗透力的行动
of their understanding,
带着他们的理解力的人
they are the ones who experience, learn, experience,
他们是那些经历 学习 经历
learn, experience, learn.
学习 经历 学习的人
They do not allow their mind to play on them,
他们不允许他们的想法影响他们
"No, no, no.
不 不 不
This mind of mine has got experiences of the past,
我的这个想法已经获取了过去的经验
and is based on that. No, I have to take everyday
而且以此为基础 不行  我必须把每一天
a new experience
当做全新的体验
and that experience must be silenced within me,
那些经验必须沉默在我内在
must be sustained within me,
必须持续在我内在
must be conditioned within me."
必须受制约在我内在
Sahaja Yoga experiences are the good conditionings,
霎哈嘉瑜伽经验是很好的制约
"How can it be? I've seen it,
怎么会呢 我已经看到过
I have faced it, I've had it. How can it be?".
我已经面对了 我已经经历过 它怎么会
But for that also, to have the best experiences,
但这也是 要想有最好的经历
first condition is of Rutambhara Pragnya,
首要条件是Rutambhara Pragnya
where you should be of that level
你应该在这一水平
that you really get those experiences,
就是你真的获得那样的经历
otherwise you'll be just a mundane type of a person all the time,
否则你将一直只是一个在世俗型的人
and you may live with Me,
你可能会和我在一起
but you will not have those experiences,
但是你将不会有那样的经历
you'll not have that blissful feeling,
你将不会有那种充满喜乐的感觉
nothing, that joy.
什么都没有 那种喜乐
So this penetration starts by your meditation
因此 这种突破始于你的冥想
and sustenance of the meditation,
和冥想的支持
and the Samadhi seed sprouting,
三摩地的种子发芽
manifesting the new dimension within.
新的维度随之显现
This sort of an attention, one has to develop,
这种类型的注意力 你要去发展
by watching the attention, Chitta Nirodha.
通过观察这注意力 洁净注意力
As you watch your money,
当你观察你的金钱
as you watch your road when you drive,
当你在开车时观察你的路
as you watch your child when it is growing,
当你的孩子成长时你观察他们
as you watch the beauty of your wife,
当你觉察你妻子的美丽
or the care of your husband.
或者你丈夫的关怀
All put together, you watch yourself, your attention,
所有的放在一起 你观察你自己 你的注意力
where is it going?
它去了哪里
Where is it lagging behind?
它掉落到哪里了
What is happening to my attention?
我的注意力发生了什么
Such people have no problems.
这样的人就没有问题
You'll be surprised, that such people
你将会惊讶 这样的人
when they want to do something it becomes dynamic.
当他们想做什么事情的时候 事情就会变得自动自发
They can work it out. Nobody has any problem,
他们可以成就  没有人有任何问题
and if there is a problem,
如果有一个问题
which you are facing all the time,
你一直面对的问题
in you then know there is something wrong with you.
在你内在 就知道你在某些方面出了问题
Something is wrong with the instrument.
这个工具出了点状况
If you don't have a tin cutter
如果你没有一个开罐头的刀
and you start using a knife to cut a tin, doesn't work out.
然后你用一个刀去切罐头 是搞不定的
Then you'll say, "The tin is, something wrong with the tin",
然后你就会说 是这个罐头 这个罐头有问题
or something wrong with you?
或者是你有什么问题
No, it's wrong with the instrument
不是 是这个工具出了问题
and that instrument has to be corrected.
而这个工具必须要修正
When the instrument is all right,
当这个工具好了
after all, with all the powers you have,
终究 你是拥有所有的力量的
with all the blessings you have,
你是拥有所有的祝福的
and the source of power behind it,
力量的源泉就在它的背后
everything should work out. It should work out.
所有的一切都要成就 它应该成就
You have had experiences of things working out.
你已经有事情被成就过的经历
You have had experiences
你有那样的经历
of many of miracles happening before your eyes,
那么多的奇迹在你眼前发生
but still the attention has not settled down
但是注意力仍然没有被安顿下来
with those experiences. Still 'gatanubhavas'
在那样的经历后 仍然'gatanubhavas'
means the old experiences continue.
意思就是旧的经历继续持续
Old identifications continue.
旧有的认同继续存在
You still continue with that
你依然继续
and the filth of that is still on your being.
那些不洁仍然在你内在存在
Change everything.
改变一切
Become a fresh new person.
成为一个新生的全新的人
You are blooming out as a flower
你盛放得像一朵花
and then as a tree
然后像一棵树
and assume your position.
然后呈现你的姿态
Assume your position as the Sahaj yogi.
呈现你的姿态为一名霎哈嘉瑜伽仕
So this attention must be brought round.
因此这样的注意力一定要恢复清醒知觉
You judge yourself, where is your attention
你看看你自己 你的注意力在哪里
and what is the point of understanding?
理解的要点是什么
What is the measure of understanding?
理解的程度是什么
It's very simple: I have to be pleased.
这非常简单 我必须高兴
Because I'm the attention.
因为我就是这注意力
If I am pleased then you have done the job.
如果我高兴 你的工作就完成了
But I cannot be pleased by mundane things,
但是我无法因世俗的事情而被取悦
by any arguments with that, but only by your ascent.
通过任何事物（都无法被取悦） 只有通过你的升进
So you judge yourself on that.
因此你用这个来裁定自己
Whether you give Me a flower,
你是否给我花朵
or anything
或者任何事物
I'm only pleased when the essence of that doing
但我只能被取悦 当做事情的本质
has that height, has that special manifestation.
达到那样的高度 有那样特殊的显现
You say, "I love you very much Mother."
你说 母亲我特别爱您
All right, you say,
好 你说
but I must see that love that you are saying,
但是 我必须要看到你说的那样的爱
or doing, has that essence that gives Me joy.
或者做的 有可以给我喜乐的本质
It's such a mutual thing between us, you can't imagine.
在我们之间 它是那样相互的 你无法想象
I can't live without you and you can't live without Me.
你不能离开我而生存 我也没法离开你而存在
It's so mutual.
它是那样相互的
But from one side
但是从一方面说
it is absolutely hundred per cent benevolent.
它是完全的百分之百仁慈的
Whether I get angry with you, whether I scold you,
不论我对你生气 不论我责骂你
whether I pamper you, whether I say, "Don't do that."
不论我纵容你 不论我说 不要那样做
If I tell you, "Don't come very close to Me. Keep away",
如果我告诉你 不要挨我太紧 走远点
anything that I do like that, is benevolent
任何我做的那样的事情 都是为你好
to you.
对你来说
And to Me the benevolence is only one,
而对我 好处只有一个
that you should be emancipated,
那就是你应该被解放
that you should gain something out of Me,
那就是你应该从我这里得到什么
that you should prosper out of Me.
那就是你应该因我而繁荣
Like the Mother Earth feels so elated
就像大地母亲感觉非常兴奋
to see Her manifestation into these beautiful green trees,
当看见她显化成那些美丽的翠绿的树
it's like that. She's nothing. We stand on Her, we walk on Her.
就像那样 她什么都不是 我们站在她身体上 我们在她身体上走路
Where do we see Her? But She sees us, in those.
我们在哪里能看见她  但是她看着我们 在那里
It's a same sort of a situation.
这是同样的情况
She is the one who changes all the seasons.
她就是那个改变所有季节的人
'Rutambhara' means the one, the attention,
'Rutambhara'意思是 注意力
which changes the seasons. 'Rutu' means the seasons.
它改变季节  'Rutu'的意思是季节
So all the seasons are created by Her
她创造出的所有季节
just to please us.
只为令我们欢喜
But what do we do, to please Her?
但是我们做了什么 去取悦她呢
We exhaust Her, torture Her,
我们使她筋疲力尽 折磨她
take out everything from Her, pollute it,
从她那里掠取所有的一切 污染它
do all kinds of nonsensical things,
做各种各样荒谬的事情
and then She gets angry.
然后她就生气了
The same thing that She is Love.
这和她是爱是同一回事
In the same love She becomes angry,
在同样的爱里 她变得生气
and then you have volcanoes, and you have earthquakes,
然后你们就有了火山爆发 你们就有了地震
and all kinds of things happening to you.
各种各样的事情发生在你们身上
But of course your Mother takes time to get angry.
但是 当然你们的母亲生气要花些时间
Takes time. That doesn't mean you take time.
花些时间 但这并不代表你可以慢慢来
Look after yourselves, it's very important.
照顾好你自己 这点非常重要
Suddenly you will find elevated.
突然间你会发现被提升了
Some people will just elevate themselves
一些人将会提升他们自己
and others will be completely cut out.
而另一些将会被完全剔除
So be careful, I'm warning.
所以要小心 我在警告
So today is the day, previous day to this fifteenth day.
因此今天是这样一天  第十五天的前一天
And the fourteenth day, one has to become a killer.
第十四天 你要成为一个杀手
Killer of all that is ignorance,
杀掉那些所有愚昧的
of all that is stupid, idiotic,
所有那些愚蠢的 白痴的
all that is cunning and all that is emotional.
所有那些狡猾的 所有那些情绪化的
Kill that part, become a Sahaja Yogi,
杀掉那部分 成为一个霎哈嘉瑜伽仕
tomorrow, to receive the blessings.
明天 接受祝福
May God Bless you.
愿神祝福你